good afternoon everyone so I apologize I
大家下午好，所以我很抱歉我
have to I'm going to sit mostly through
要我去主要是通过坐
this lecture I managed to do something
这个讲座我设法 做一些事情
to my knee yesterday and I'm having
我的膝盖昨天，我有
trouble moving around very much but
麻烦 走动 非常 多 ，但
today what we're going to talk about is
今天我们要谈 的是
input/output what it looks like from the
输入/输出是什么样子从
programmers perspective and this is a
程序员的角度，这是一个
you've already learned instead of a lot
你已经学到了很多东西，而不是
of the standard UNIX libraries for like
标准的UNIX库一样的
printf and scanf and those routines and
printf和scanf函数和那些套路和
we'll talk about them a little but what
我们将谈论他们一点 ，但什么
will first talk about is actually lower
先说说实际上是低
level i/o stuff that is directly
级I / O 的东西，是直接
interfacing to the operating system and
接口到操作系统 和
this is what you're going to need to
这就是 你接下来 要做的 事情 需要
learn about partly some of this material
了解部分的一些这种材料
you're going to need for the next web
你将需要在未来网络
that comes out at midnight tonight the
那今晚午夜 了出来
shell lab and you'll need to also you'll
外壳实验室，你需要同时你会
be revisiting this several other labs
要重新审视 这几个其它实验室
along the course including the final web
沿当然包括最终网
the the web proxy web so this is sort of
在Web代理网络进行，因此这是有点
where we're we're really digging down
在那里我们我们真的挖下去
deeply into this type of programming you
深入到这种类型 的节目，你
do if you're writing system software
做，如果你正在编写系统软件
things that are very just barely above
事情是非常勉强上方
the operating system level and I know
在操作系统 层面，我知道
for myself of learning this material I
为自己 学习这些材料我的
actually learned this material from 213
其实从 213了解到这种材料
my co-author David Halloran is the one
我的合着者戴维·哈洛伦 是一个
who knew this stuff already
谁知道这个东西了
he wrote that part of the book I learned
他写这本书我学到的那部分
it by reading the book just like you are
它通过阅读 这本书就像 你
but I found it actually very useful to
但 我发现 它 其实非常有用
know and a variety of different other
知道和各种不同的其他的
situations I've been in in the meantime
情况下，我一直在此期间
this is quite a few years ago and so I
这是一个相当几年前，所以我
think it's worth understanding and I'll
认为这是值得的理解，我会
also mention this kind of material
还别说这种物质
usually is taught you don't really see
通常是教你实在不明白
it covered in most books except for ones
它在大多数书涵盖除了 那些
that are really oriented toward system
被计入系统真正面向
programmers and are fairly arcane or you
程序员和相当神秘，或者你
try and learn it by reading man pages
试图通过阅读手册页了解它
and that's a fairly cryptic way to try
那就是去尝试一个相当隐蔽的方式
and understand
和理解
and a sort of a set of abstractions
和排序一组抽象的
provided by an API so I hope you'll find
通过 API 提供的 ，所以我希望你会 发现
this useful so what we'll talk about
这很有用，这样我们将 谈论
then is that what I mentioned this
那么是什么我提到这个
low-level i/o that I supported by UNIX
低级别的I / O，我通过UNIX支持
and other related operating systems and
和其他相关的操作系统和
then a package called Rio which stands
然后被叫力 包 其代表
to robust IO oh and you will actually
强劲 IO 哦，你居然会
not be using this package until the last
不能采用这种封装形式，直到 最后
lab for the course the proxy lab at
实验室的课程在 代理 实验室
which time you'll use it a lot but it's
这时候你会经常使用它，但它
worth looking at and partly it's in the
值得看的，另一部分是在
book it's well documented in the book
本书是在 书中有据可查
and if you really want to understand how
如果你 真的想了解如何
software works or a system works the
软件工程或系统的工作
best thing you can do is if you've if it
你能做的最好的事情是，如果 你已经，如果它
there's good quality source code to look
有好品质的源代码查看
at and study you can learn a lot from
在学习你可以学到很多东西
doing that and I really recommend for
这样做，我真的推荐
that chapter in the book that you go
在你去的书 章
ahead and study all of the code that
进取，学习所有的代码是
makes up Rio it's not a huge amount and
弥补了力拓这不是一个巨大的数额和
just getting for the subtlety is
刚开的微妙之处
involved in how you deal with errors how
涉及如何处理错误如何
you deal with exceptional conditions and
你处理特殊情况和
things like that and then we'll talk to
这样的事情，然后我们会跟
them about how files are represented the
他们对文件是如何表示的
sort of various data structures behind
排序各种数据结构的背后
files how they support standard i/o and
文件如何支持标准I / O和
i/o redirection and unix and also talk
I / O重定向和 UNIX， 还 谈
about the so-called buffered i/o the i/o
关于所谓的 缓冲I / O的I / O
that you're more familiar with and see
你是比较熟悉的，看
when you use printf and scanf so UNIX
当你用printf和scanf等等UNIX
actually has a much simpler and more
其实有一个更简单，更
unified view of i/o than any other
我的统一视图/ O比任何其他
operating system it's one of the nice
操作系统它是很好的一个
design features of it is that a lot of
它的设计特点是，很多的
abstractions are built into the notion
抽象内置于概念
of a file and a file is really just a
文件 和文件实际上只是一个
sequence of bytes and in UNIX does not
字节和UNIX顺序不
distinguish between different classes of
不同类别的区分
files unlike say Windows or earlier
不像说的Windows或更早版本的文件
versions of Macintosh operating system
Macintosh操作系统的版本
it just thanks to them as fights and the
它只是感谢他们为打架和
operating system level has essentially
操作系统级别都有本质
no understanding of a more detailed
没有更详细的了解
structure inside of a file
文件的内部结构
and one of the things it does is a file
和它做的事情之一就是文件
is normally originally thought of is
通常最初的想法 是的
something that stored on say a disk
存储上的东西说盘
drive or some other external storage
驱动器或 一些其他外部存储
device and that you open you read it or
设备和你打开 你读它或
write it you close it those sort of
写 你关闭它的排序
standard operations but UNIX also use
标准操作，而且还UNIX使用
the notion of a file to represent many
文件的概念来表示多
other different things including for
其他不同的东西，包括 对
example the devices that are the i/o
例子是将I / O设备
devices that are connected to a
连接到一个设备
particular machine the tty stands for
特殊的机器TTY代表
teletype which is a antique terminology
电传其是古董术语
for how people used to actually
对于人们如何使用实际
interface typewriters to computers the
接口打字机电脑
other thing that our viewed as like
我们 像 看其它东西
files are the network connections what
文件的网络连接是什么
are known as sockets and when you do
被称为插座，当你做
communication over the Internet you do
在你做互联网通信
it by you send a message by writing to a
它通过您通过写入发送消息
socket and you accept incoming
插座，你接受传入
communication by reading from a socket
通过从套接字中读取通信
and so the same low-level of API is the
等 API 的相同的低级别 是
same whether you're reading or writing
同样无论你是在读或写
files on your disk drive or sending
磁盘驱动器或发送的文件
packets over the Internet
在互联网上的数据包
so the core operations then associated
所以核心业务相关的再
with files of course are opening and
当然是有文件被打开和
closing them and reading and writing
关闭它们，阅读 和写作
them the other sort of attribute that's
他们的其他种类的属性的 这
associated with most but not all files
与大多数但不是所有的文件关联
is what's called the file position so
是什么所谓 的文件位置，
again if you imagine when you're reading
再次，如果当你读你想象
from a file you don't want to always
从文件中你不想总是
start at the beginning every time you do
每次你做一次从头开始
a read you you read some data and then
读你，你读一些数据，然后
you read some more data and so that's a
你读更多的数据，因此这是一个
tracked by a file position which is just
通过这只是一个文件位置跟踪
a counter that says how many bytes has
一个柜台，上面写着多少字节具有
have been written read from this file so
已被写入 从该文件中 读 这么
far so that I know where to go and you
到目前为止，我知道 去 什么地方 ， 你
can actually even alter that value with
实际上 ，即使改变与价值
a various classes operation called
称为各类操作
seeking which is just a way of changing
求这只是一个改变的方式
the file pointer the position pointer
文件指针 的位置的指针
now that doesn't work too well if your
现在如果不工作也很好的
input is a terminal where you can't move
输入是 ，你不能移动 终端
you can't sort of back up and have a
你不能排序 的备份和有
recover data that was presented to it
恢复被提交给 它 的数据
earlier or jump ahead and start
早期或跳跃前进，并开始
accepting data that hasn't been typed
尚未接受输入数据
yet so there's some kinds of files have
但如此有一些类型的文件有
a file position and seeking and others
文件位置和寻求和其他
don't similarly to a network socket you
没有类似网络套接字你
can't jump up socket for it in time you
不能跳起来插座它在你的时间
can only read or write the particular
只能读取或写入特定的
packet as they come in but in general
包，因为他们进来，但一般
think of it then is the file position as
想起来了，然后是文件位置
part of the the data associated with an
在与相关联的 数据的一部分
open file that tells me how far along in
打开文件， 告诉我有多远沿
this file have I read or written and
这个文件有我读出或写入 和
then again the files there because
然后再在那里，因为文件
there's all these different things
有所有这些不同的 东西
they're sort of unified in this file
他们 那种统一在这个文件
abstraction but obviously there's
抽象但显然有
differences and different attributes to
差异和不同的属性来
them and so there's sort of many
他们，所以有几分许多
different categories and subcategories
不同类别和子类别
but the ones we'll think about our a
但那些我们会考虑一下我们的一个
regular files to think of things that
常规文件想到的东西，
are on a disk drive directories which is
都 在一个磁盘驱动器的目录 是
a directory is considered a type of file
目录被认为是一个类型的文件
meaning the data that's in there is just
意思是这样的数据， 有刚
enough as a file but of course
足够的文件，但当然
it's a special kind of file and that it
它是一种特殊的文件， 它 的
actually does have an interpretation
实际上确实有 一个解释
that entries in that file describe the
在该文件中的条目 描述
locations and attributes of other files
位置和其他文件属性
and then as I mentioned the term socket
然后正如我 所提到的术语插座
is a connection to a network and it's
是网络的连接，它的
both for sending and for receiving
既用于发送和用于接收
messages over the network there's other
在网络上的消息 有其他
files that we won't really talk about
我们不会真正谈论的文件
for example when you pipe when you from
例如，当你管，当你从
one application to another that both the
一个应用程序到另一个， 无论是
output of the first program and the
第一程序 和所述的输出
input of the second are special types of
所述第二输入是特殊类型的
files called pipes and they're handled
文件称为管道，他们正在处理
by writing is putting something into the
通过写作是把东西放到了
pipe and reading is to take something
管道和阅读是把一些东西
out of that pipe a similar something
指出，管的 类似的东西
called a symbolic link which is just a
所谓的符号链接这 仅仅是一个
way that you can have multiple names for
这样， 你可以有 多个名称
a file and pointers to a file that
文件和指向的文件
aren't really without having to make
是不是真的，而无需进行
separate copies of a file and then other
一个文件，然后其他的单独副本
special types of devices so we won't
特殊类型的设备，所以我们不会
really we'll only consider the first
真的 ，我们将 只考虑第一
three types of files and in fact for
三种类型的文件，并在事实上为
today mostly the first two so the idea
今天 主要是前两个这样的想法
of a file then is it just contains
一个文件，然后它只是包含
arbitrary data and the operating system
任意数据和操作系统
really for regular file doesn't try to
真正为常规文件不会 尝试
get into the details of what's inside
进入细节里面有什么
that file and there's some class of
该文件，并有一些类
applications that will distinguish
这将区分应用
between a text file and a binary file
文本文件和二进制文件之间
not really at the operating system level
没有真正在操作系统 级别
but more higher levels and the main
但更多更高水平和主
difference with that is that a text file
与不同的是，一个文本文件
should only have the standard characters
应该只有标准字
of ASCII or another class would be
ASCII或另一类将是
various encoding that allow you to do in
各种编码，让你做
coatings of non-english alphabets and
非英文 字母 的涂料 和
binary files would be things like an
二进制文件将是东西像
image or a actual
图像或实际
a code or a video or audio file or
代码或视频或音频 文件或
something that it's the you're within
东西，它是你中
that code there's a sequence of bytes
该代码有一个字节序列
that are encoding numbers in some form
以某种形式编码的数字
directly and then the main thing about a
直接再约的主要事情
text file is that there are certain
文本文件 是 有 一定的
functions that distinguish a newline
区分换行符功能
character meaning the end of it line of
字符意义的它线的末端
text and you already learned about that
文本和你已经了解了
character it's got the code of a zero a
字符它有一个 零 的代码
as a bytecode and that became one of the
作为一个字节码， 并且 成为了一个
forbidden codes of your attacks because
你的攻击，因为禁用码
it would be interpreted as a newline by
它会被解释 为一个 换行符
the function get ass just to mention
该功能获取 的屁股 刚刚提
that and this is one place when you're
这一点，这是一个 地方，当你
transferring files between say a Windows
说一个Windows之间传输文件
machine and a Linux or a Mac one of the
机器和Linux或Mac上的一个
things if it's a text file that has to
的事情，如果它是有一个 文本文件
be changed is the two classes of systems
被改变为两个类的系统
have different ways of interpreting of
有 解释的不同方式
encoding when is the end of a line and
编码时是一条线的端部和
in a Linux or Mac file it's just this
在Linux或Mac文件，它只是 这个
character code a which stands for line
它代表行字符代码的
feed where's the windows files finish
喂哪来的Windows文件 完成
with a tooth character end of line
与线的齿字符端
carriage return in line feed and I show
在行回车喂，我展示
you this picture of an object that
你的 对象 ，这张照片 是
you've probably only seen in museum but
你可能只看到在 博物馆 ，但
it's a typewriter and just to tell you
这是一 台打字机 ，只是告诉你
what the heck is the carriage return and
到底是什么回车 和
what's the line feed I thought you might
什么是换行符我想你可能
like to in case you've never actually
喜欢 的情况下，你从来 没有真正
used an old-fashioned typewriter
用老式打字机
basically at the end of us on the left
基本处于我们 左边的 结束
hand side of a typewriter is this bar
打字机的 右手 侧是这条
and when you start typing along I'll the
当你沿着我会在开始打字
page the this roller with your page on
页面的 这个滚轮与您的网页
it sinks along and it comes to the end
它一起下沉，并走向终结
and then you want to get back to the
然后你 想回
beginning of the next line so you want
下一行的开始，所以你要
to both do the carriage return which is
既做回车这是
this thing shove it to the right and you
这个东西 它 推 到右边，你
want to do a line
想要做一个线
feed you want the roller on it to go
喂，你想上的滚筒去
down to the next line so there's a knob
到下一个行，以便有一个旋钮
here that you can twist by hand but in
在这里，你可以 用手但在扭曲
general what you do is you type along
一般来说，你要做的就是沿着输入
and then you go slam like that and this
然后你去扣篮 这样的，这
lever both pushes the thing back and it
杠杆都推回事情，它
rotates the the roller by one lines
转动由一个线滚子
worth and so carriage return line feed
值得等回车换行符
is where that actually comes from in
在这里，实际上来自于
case you wonder and then a directory as
万一你不知道，然后一个目录
I mentioned it's it's stored as a file
我提到这是它作为 文件 存储
but it's a file that the operating
但它是一个文件操作
system eats the filesystem part of the
系统吃 的 文件系统的一部分
operating system actually interprets in
实际上 ，操作系统在解释
very specific ways and as you know
非常具体的方式和你也知道
within every directory there's two
每个目录内有两家
special files dot and dot dot referring
特殊文件DOT和点点参考
to the local file and its parent in the
本地文件和其 母公司在
tree structure and so in in most systems
树结构等在大多数系统
systems that I know of there's a sort of
据我所知，有一个排序的系统
hierarchical organization to the files
分层组织的文件
we're not going to talk much about file
我们不会谈论 太多的文件
systems but there's a hierarchical
系统，但有一个分层
organization and that maintained this a
组织和维持这个
series of files each being the directory
一系列的文件 都应当是目录
and the directory then it's a pointer to
与目录，然后 它是一个指针
its sub directory which again are files
其子目录这又是 文件
and so what's referred to in UNIX
还等什么 在Unix 的简称
terminology and most other operating
术语和大多数其他操作系统
systems what's known as a path name is a
作为路径名称是什么已知的系统
way to navigate through this hierarchy
办法通过这个层次 导航
of files and identify one particular one
文件， 并确定一个特定的一个
and so that all comes to say that the
并且使所有来说，
low-level
低级别
UNIX operations that use to implement
使用实现UNIX操作
this are to open a file to read it and
这是打开 文件读取它，
write it and to close it and those
写和关闭它 和那些
literally those are the names of the
从字面上那些的名字
functions so the open function then you
功能如此开放的功能，那么你
give a path name and remember pathnames
提供一个路径名和路径名记
can be absolute meaning that they start
可以是绝对的意义，他们开始
with a slash and they go all the way
以斜线和他们一路走
down the hierarchy they can be relative
沿层次 ，他们可以是相对的
to
至
particular whatever your current
特别是无论你目前的
directory is where and they can also be
目录是，他们也可以
relative to a user if you use the tilde
相对于用户如果使用波浪号
slash or tilde L then that sort of a
斜线或波浪大号那么那样的
shortcut in this path name to get to
此路径名快捷方式去
particular users so a path name can be
特别是用户，这样的路径名即可
any of those forms when you open it it
任何这些形式的，当你打开它，它
just has to be some way that just like
只是必须有某种方式，就像
you specify in other places that you
你在其他地方指定您
tell where this particular file is
分不清哪里这个特殊的文件
you're trying to open and so it's given
你试图 打开，因此它给
a path name and then it's given a
路径名，然后给了一个
integer code that says what do you want
整数码，说你想要什么
to do when you open this file
当你打开 这个文件做
in what form do you want to open it and
以何种形式你想打开它 ，
that specified die series of constants
该指定的模具系列常数
that are already predefined when you
那些已经 预定义，当你
include the propria and you can and
包括固有你可以和
those actually get bitwise each of those
那些真正得到各按位的那些
is a one bit flag in a power of two
是二 的幂一个一位标志，
position or it's a position one bit in a
位置或它的位置在一个位
field somewhere and so you can logically
场的地方，所以你可以顺理成章地
or those together if you want multiple
或者那些在一起，如果你想多
combinations so for example I can say
这样的组合，例如，我可以说
read-only I can say read and write I can
只读我可以说，读，写，我可以
say append meaning don't if I'm opening
说追加意义不，如果我打开
it to write don't begin it the don't
它写 不开始它的不
start writing at the beginning start
创业之初开始写
writing it wherever the end of the file
写它无论在 文件 的结尾
is now so all those can be down to this
现在这么所有这些可以 下到这
is described in the book by using the
通过使用在书中描述
right set of names of constants and
正确的常量集的名称和
oaring them together and that will
oaring在一起，这将
return something that's called a file
返回的东西，就是所谓的文件
descriptor and that's a very important
描述，这是一个 非常重要的
idea that and one of the reasons why
想法 和的原因之一
we're talking about this today this is
我们今天在谈论这个 ，这是
going to be very important in your lab
要在您的实验室很重要
it's the notion of a file descriptor
这是 一个文件描述符的概念
which is just a small integer that lists
这只是一个小的整数列出
which particular one of the open files
其中特别是 打开的文件之一
that's being used by this particular
多数民众赞成正在使用这种特殊的
program are you referring to and so it's
计划你 指的，所以它是
a small number because these are a time
少数，因为这些都是时间
sequentially when you
顺序，当你
in your program than you run and you're
在你的程序跑得比你和你
in fact limited on most machines to some
实际上限制在大多数机器上的一些
some bounded number of open files you're
的 你 打开文件的 一些有限数量的
allowed to have at any time in fact if
允许有在如果事实上 任何时间
you go to see on if you're on the
你去看看。如果你在
machine and you type in limits limit
机器和 你在限制限制类型
you'll see there that entry called
你会看到 那里，进入所谓的
descriptors 10:24 says that you can't
描述10:24说，你不能
have more than a thousand 24 files open
有 一千多 24个文件 打开
at any given time and in fact if you've
在任何给定时间，其实如果你已经
got a thousand 24 files open it's a
有一千个24个文件打开它是一个
chance you're doing something really
机会，你真的做的事情
seriously wrong being that you haven't
严重的问题在于你有没有
been closing the files you should be
被关闭的文件，你应该
closing
关闭
and all of the system calls including
和所有的系统调用 ，包括
these always have a return code and the
这些始终有一个返回代码和
return codes vary sometimes a negative
返回代码有时会发生变化 的负
number is an error sometimes a zero is
数是一个错误 有时 是零
an error they're all different and all
一个错误，他们都是不同的 ，所有
confusing and all inscrutable so you
混乱和所有不可思议的 ，所以你
have to look at the documentation for
不得不看的文档
every single one of those functions and
这些功能的 每 一个和一个
one of the the rules we're going to
的，我们要的规则之一
hammer away at in this course is every
锤离开在这个课程是每个
time you make a system call you should
时间你做一个系统调用，你应该
check the return code to see if there's
检查返回代码 ，看看是否有
an error and then do some appropriate
一个错误，然后做一些适当的
way of handling the error that's just a
处理这只是一个错误 的方式
practice it's a pain in the butt it
实践它在屁股痛它
makes your code look like a rat's nest
使你的代码看起来像一个老鼠窝
of conditionals is you really would
条件句是你真的会
rather not because often there's an
而不是因为经常有一个
error you deciding what you're going to
错误你决定你要什么
do when there's an error is harder than
做的时候有一个误差大于更难
then figuring just ignoring it all
然后盘算只是忽略了这 一切
together and so there's a lot of code
在一起，所以有大量 的代码
out there where people just cross their
在那里，人们刚刚越过他们的
fingers and hope there's never errors in
手指和希望从未有误差
their system calls but we're going to
他们的系统调用，但我们要
really push on you hard to say every
真正推动你很难说每
time you make a system call check the
时间你做一个系统调用检查
return code and do something if it's not
返回代码，并做一些事情，如果不是
right and so the open will return a
右等开放将返回
number so that it's an int that it
号码， 以便 它是一个 int，它
returns but if it's a negative number
回报，但如果它是一个负数
that means it couldn't open the the file
这 意味着它无法打开该文件
for example the file doesn't exist or
例如文件不 存在或
you're trying to open it in a mode that
你想 在一个模式下打开它 那
you're not authorized to open again so
你无权这样 再次打开
there are three particular file
有三个 特定文件
descriptors associated with every single
与每一个相关的描述符
process that runs one is standard input
运行一个 过程 是标准的输入
the other standard output and the third
其他标准输出和 所述第三
is standard error and they always have a
是标准的错误，他们总是有一
file descriptor number zero one and two
文件描述符数零一和 二
and so that you shouldn't really refer
所以，你不应该确指
to them by their file descriptor numbers
他们通过自己的文件描述符号
even though you actually can reliably
即使你实际上可以可靠地
depend on those values simply if you
依靠这些值 只是，如果 你
want to close the file you also open you
要关闭也打开你的文件
see you give a path name and a one bit a
看你给的路径名和一个有点
one integer field that gives these flags
一个整数字段，让这些标志
say something about the modes in which
说说模式中
you want to open it to close a file you
要 打开关闭文件你
just say close and you give the file
只是说 接近，你给的文件
descriptor number not the name of the
文件描述符 的 不是 名称
file and it returns a return code too so
文件并返回一个返回代码， 也因此
you might say now why in the world could
现在你可能会说， 为什么在世界 上 能
you ever get an error closing a file if
你曾经得到一个错误关闭，如果一个文件
it's open and the answers that actually
它的开放和答案实际上是
can happen in particular we'll see when
尤其可以发生，我们会看到，当
we have multi-threaded programs where
我们拥有多线程程序，其中
it's possible to have to essentially two
它可能有 两个基本
programs running at the same time
在同一时间运行的程序
sharing their data structures and
分享他们的数据结构和
interacting with each other sharing
相互共享互动
their memory it's very important kind of
他们的记忆是非常重要的一种
programming and one that you can really
编程和一个你 可真
make bad horrible mistakes in and one of
做坏可怕的失误和一个
the bad horrible mistakes is if you try
坏可怕的错误是，如果你尝试
to close the file that's already been
关闭这已经 得到 了文件
closed
关闭
it'll be an error and that can happen if
这将是一个错误， 可 如果 发生
there's two different parts of your
有两个不同的部分你
program running and each of them tries
程序运行和他们每个人的尝试
to close the file so in the book and in
关闭文件，以便在书和
the in this code you'll see we
在这段代码中，你会看到我们
introduced some error handling routines
介绍了一些错误处理例程
one of which is called P error and all
其中一个被称为P错误和所有
it does is print some not whatever
它是打印一些没有任何
message you want to print and then it
消息要打印，然后
exits the program or no I guess it
退出程序或没有我想这
doesn't the I'll mention it a little
不将我会提到这一点
while it just prints an error message
虽然它只是打印错误消息
but the point is even even something as
但问题是，即使连一些如
mundane as closing a file you should be
平凡如关闭文件，你应该
checking the return code okay so this is
检查返回码好了，所以这是
the function that reads of at this low
， 在这个低的 读取功能
level is called read and it's given a
级别称为读取它给了 一个
file descriptor
文件描述符
you provided a pointer to a buffer that
你提供一个指向缓冲区
you you've had to allocate either
你你已经分配 或者
aesthetically or via malloc and you also
美学 或通过malloc和也
specify how long that buffer is so that
指定缓冲区有多长，这样
it can't overflow that buffer and read
它不能溢出该缓冲区，读
just means read as many bytes as you
只是意味着 读取的字节数，你
feel like
感觉
but no more than the number I tell you
但不超过数多，我告诉你
to which sounds like a weird statement
到这 听起来像一个奇怪的声明
what do you mean what you feel like well
你什么意思，你觉得什么样的好
it has to read at least one byte so if
它具有读取至少一个 字节，所以如果
for example it's a standard input it
例如，它是一个标准输入它
will hang there and wait until actually
将挂在那里， 等到实际
with standard input it will wait until
标准输入会等到
you've typed in a string and hit the
你输入一个字符串，然后打
return and it will then read at least
返回，然后它会读取至少
some fraction of that into the program
的 某些 部分 进入程序
if it's a network connection again the
如果是 再次 的网络连接
read won't just wait it will hang until
读不会只是等待它会挂起，直到
something arrives on that particular
到达的东西 在那个特定的
network connection and then read in some
网络连接，然后在一些阅读
number of bytes that have been sent to
已发送的 字节数
it and I'm being vague by saying some
它和 我说一些含糊其辞
number because the truth is it there's
数字，因为事实是它有
no guarantee it will read any fixed
不能保证 它会读取任何固定
number of bytes it will read at least
字节数将至少读
one and it won't read any more than that
之一，它不会读取比 这更
buffer is but the number between that
缓冲器是但之间的数
might be variable and so when it reads
可能是可变的，所以当它读取
less than that the number of maximum
小于该最大数目
number of bytes you specify that's
字节数您指定 的
called a short read and that can and
称为短 读取，并且可以和
does happen and you have to write your
确实发生了，你 必须 写
code expecting it and we'll talk about
代码期待它和我们谈谈
that a little bit
这一点
oh and so again and by Reed returns an
哦，等再次和 里德返回
assigned number actually of data type F
分配数实际上数据 F 型的
size T like SS ize underscore t which is
像 SS 码 T IZE下划线吨这 是
typically a long int so a potentially
通常为长整型这样一个潜在的
negative number in it that that number
在它负数认为这个数字
is if it's a zero it means that it's hit
是如果它是 一个零这意味着它的 命中
it's detected and in the file that
它检测并在文件中
you've run to the end of the stored file
你已经运行到存储的文件的末尾
that the network connection has been
该网络连接已经
closed or something has happened if it's
关闭或事情发生 ，如果它是
positive then that the number of bytes
正则 该 字节数
that were read and if it's negative it's
已读，如果它是负它的
an error code
错误代码
so as I mentioned if it if it reads
所以正如我所说，如果它是否读取它
fewer than the number of bytes you
不是字节 的数量少你
specify that's referred to as a short
指明一个被称为短
count and I'll talk about why that would
算，我会谈谈为什么这样做
occur writing is sort of the same idea
发生写作是那种同样的 想法 的
that you provide a file descriptor you
您提供的文件描述符 你
provide a buffer where the the data that
提供一个缓冲器，其中 所述数据
you want to write out is stored and you
要写出 存储和你
give up how many bytes long do you want
放弃了多少个字节长做 你想做
your right to be and it will write some
你的权利，并会写一些
number of bytes to the output at least
的字节数到 输出至少
one and no more than n byte but it might
一个也没有超过n字节以上，但它可能
not be all of them which is kind of
不是所有的人这是 一种
weird because you said I want to write
奇怪，因为你说我想写
this I want to send it to a file I want
这个我想将它发送到一个文件我想
to send it over the Internet but it can
送它 在 互联网 上 ，但它可以
potentially not send them all and we'll
可能不会向他们所有的，我们将
we'll talk about that a little bit so
我们将谈论的是 那么 一点点
again that's called a short right and
再这就是所谓的 短右
similarly it will return the number of
同样它将返回的 数量
bytes that were written and so if it's
过去写到所以如果它的字节
less than zero that's an error code so
小于 零这是 一个错误代码，以便
just to give you a really simple example
只给 你一个非常简单的 例子
of this in action this code does what
这此代码的运行做了什么
you call echoing meaning that you type
你叫呼应您键入的意义
in something and it will print it out
在东西，它会打印出来
and it does it in the most mundane way
并且它在它最 平凡的方式
possible by reading specifying a single
可以通过读取指定单个
byte read and single byte right so you
字节读取单个字节正确，因此您
remember I told you read will read at
记得我告诉过你阅读将在阅读
least one byte but no more than the
至少一个字节，但没有比多
number you've told it so when you give
数你告诉它，当你给
it one it means it will read exactly one
这一个就意味着它会读取只有一个
byte and similarly with right if you say
字节和类似与你说的对
right one byte that that's guaranteed to
右一个字节是有保证 到
happen
发生
and so this is really really bad code in
所以这是真的很糟糕的代码
the sense that call to read or to write
调用 读或写的感
the system level call it's a relatively
系统级调用它是一个相对
expensive call it means kicking your
昂贵的调用就意味着你踢
whole operation up to the operating
整个操作到操作
system doing what's called a context
系统 做什么所谓的上下文
switch meaning it will go into the
切换意味着它将进入
kernel of the system invoke operating
该系统的核心则启动运行
system functions do whatever the reader
系统功能做任何读者
right tells it to
它的权利告诉给
to come back out switch back to your job
回来了切换回你的工作
and that will typically take maybe
而且通常会采取可能
20,000 to 40,000 clock cycles which you
20,000至40,000个时钟周期，你
know a clock cycle nowadays is less than
知道一个时钟周期时下小于
a nanosecond so you say yeah it's a
纳秒 所以你说的没错这就是一个
you're talking maybe 10 microseconds
你说的10 微秒
what's the big deal there but that'll
有什么大不了的存在，但该会
add up if you start sending long files
积少成多，如果你开始发送长文件
out over you know millions of bytes if
出过，你知道数百万字节，如果
you start sending them a one byte at a
你开始在向他们发送一个字节
time you'll spend most of that time
时间你会花大部分时间
sitting in the operating system going
坐在操作系统会
going crazy so this is not a good idea
快要疯了，所以这是不是 一个好主意
but it does work and that's actually a
但它的工作， 这就是 一个实际
easy mistake you can make the programmer
容易犯的错误，你可以让 程序员
is to not use it is to use this
是不使用 它 就是 用这个
low-level writing and reading and the
低级别的 写入和读取和
program will function fine it's just it
计划将发挥罚款，它只是它
will be really really slow but just to
将 是非常 非常慢 ，但只是为了
give you a demo of this idea of calls
给你这个想法呼叫的演示
the operating system there's a pretty
操作系统有一个非常
cool
凉
so this program and this is on the web
所以这个程序，这 是 在网络 上
linked off the webpage the code for this
连结过的网页的代码本
lecture so this one called
讲座所以这个叫
CPE standard in meaning copy standard
在意义副本标准CPE标准
input is just the code I showed you and
输入刚才的代码我发现你和
so if you type something it will just
所以，如果你输入 的东西它只是
echo it back so it's reading in so it
回声回去，这样它的 读取，因此
looks to you and to me like it's a
看起来你和我 就像是一个
reading on line of text and then echoing
阅读的文本行，然后呼应
it back but what it's actually doing is
它回来，但它实际上做的 是
again the interface to the terminal is
再次接口向所述终端是
one that it doesn't actually wake up
一个，它实际上并没有醒过来
this code until it gets a complete line
这个代码，直到它得到的完整产品线
but it's actually just printing these
但它实际上 只是 这些 打印
characters back one one character at a
字符回到一个一个字符
time and I can demo that by there's a
时间，我可以演示，通过有一个
pretty interesting facility called
所谓非常有趣的设施
tracing s trace then what s chase will
跟踪中的痕迹，然后有何 追涨意愿
do if you give it the name of a program
做，如果你给它 一个程序的名字
is it will detect every every system
是它会检测每家每户系统
call that you make every basically
叫你尽一切基本上
called to the operating system functions
所谓的操作系统功能
that you make when you run a program and
您所做的，当你运行一个程序，并
it will generally view out this huge
它通常会 查看了 这个巨大
amount of inscrutable stuff that you
高深莫测的东西，量你
don't really want to see I'll just show
真的不希望看到我就展示
you this Oh
你这个 哦
it's telling you logging every single
它告诉你记录每一个
call and it's usually way too much stuff
打电话，它通常是太多东西
so the more useful way to do this is to
所以 要做到这一点 比较有用 的方法 是
give it an argument that says I only
给它， 只有我 说的论据
want to watch some limited class of
想观看一些类的有限
functions of when this is running and so
当这个功能运行等
what I just want our calls to the right
我只是希望我们的呼吁向右
the low level output right and you'll
低电平输出 右拐，你就会
see that what happens then is this
看到发生了什么，然后是这个
string i typed in I turned into a series
字符串我在我输入变成了一系列
of 1 byte right calls to the low level
1个字节的权利要求为低电平
right function
右功能
and of course some way I could show you
当然还有一些方法，我可以告诉你
the reeds and right try that
芦苇 和 右侧尝试
and it's all confused because I'm I'm
和它的所有困惑，因为我是我
messing this comes out on standard error
这搞乱出来的标准错误
but on the terminal it sort of
但在终端上， 它像是
interleaving standard error and standard
交织标准错误和 标准
out so it's kind of messy to look at but
出这么它是一种 乱 看，但
again you can see that it's taking my
再次，你可以 看到它正在我
characters and it's reading 1 and
字符，它的阅读和1
writing 1 in this loop so let's see
在这个循环中写1 让我们 看看
control D to get out of it back to the
控制用 DA 摆脱它回
code
码
so what's this short count business why
有啥这短短数企业为什么
would that occur well there's a couple
会出现很好的一对夫妇
ones as I mentioned if you counter an
那些正如我所说，如果你对付的
end-of-file you're not going to read in
档案结尾你不会阅读
however many bytes you're given for the
你给出了然而，许多字节
buffer if you are reading text lines
缓冲区如果你正在阅读的文本行
from a terminal the terminal
从终端的终端
handler will just send a wine two words
处理程序将只发送一个葡萄酒 两个字
at a time with the newline character
在与换行符时间
terminating it if you're reading or
终止它，如果你正在阅读或
writing a network packet the way network
写一个网络数据包的网络方式
packets work is that or messages if you
包的工作是， 或消息，如果你
have a big long message it's broken into
有一个大的长消息它分成
smaller chunks typically about a
较小的块通常为约 一
thousand bytes or so question if you are
千个字节左右，如果你是质疑
trying to read from an end-of-file where
试图从最终的文件在哪里阅读
we turn 0 is that a short count it's a
我们把0是很短的计数 这是一个
really short count yes but it's not a
真的很短算 肯定的，但它不是一个
negative yes so as it says here if you
负是这样它说，在这里，如果你
encounter an in your file it'll actually
在你的文件 ，它会真正 遇到
there's two things actually it's a
这事实上是两件事情 它是一个
really good question if you're like near
如果你喜欢近非常好的 问题
the end of a file you have 100 bytes
文件的 最后 ，你有 100个字节
left and you say read 200 your first
左，你说读200的第一
call to read will come back and get 100
调用read会回来拿到100
character it would say 100 and it will
性格会说100，它会
get that number and then you call again
拿到号码，然后你 再 打电话
the second time and it will return 0 and
第二次，它会返回 0，
so that's how you actually detect the
所以这就是你如何实际检测
true end of file as opposed to you know
文件 的真正结束 ，而不是你 知道
some other reason you might have gotten
你 可能已经找到了一些其他原因
a short count is if that you actually
短短数是，如果你确实
get a read of 0 the only case you'll get
获得读取 0的唯一情况下，你会得到
at 4 is an end of file so that's a good
在4文件的末尾所以这是一个很好的
question thanks so again if over the
问题 感谢这么一次，如果在
Internet typically packets are round a
互联网通常包是一个圆
thousand bytes it's actually depends on
它实际上取决于几千字节
what where it's gone through what layers
什么地方它是通过什么层了
in the protocols it's gone through but
在协议它通过了，但
1500 bytes is actually the standard what
1500个字节实际上是什么标准
they call minimum transmission unit so
他们称之为最小传输单元，从而
if you have a big long file will come
如果你有一个很长的文件会
back and in blocks like that and if
背部和这样的，如果块
you're trying to read into a larger
你想读入一个更大的
buffer
缓冲
it will typically come back in chunk
它通常会回来的大块
question no in other words your and
没有换句话说 问题 你 和
again if you're writing code you
如果再你写的代码你
shouldn't expect any number particularly
不应指望任何数量特别
it will be dependent on the
这将是依赖于
implementation no because I'm only I'm
没有实施 ，因为我只我很
only reading or writing one character at
只有在阅读或书写在一个字符
a time right so I guess you're asking
一时间 正确的 ，所以我想你 问
what if I like spent of a weak typing
如果我喜欢花了弱类型的
characters in a really long string and
在一个很长的字符串中的字符和
hit return I don't know if you try it
打回 我不知道，如果你试试吧
let me know the answer but it will cause
让我知道了答案，但它会 引起
an error but that part believe me
一个错误，但该部分相信我
they've really gone through that code a
他们真的已经通过代码不见了
lot of times and and gotten rid of all
很多次，并摆脱了 所有 的
those lurking buffer overflow
这些潜伏的缓冲区溢出
vulnerabilities in the code but will let
在代码，但会让漏洞
you do it I don't actually know but
你做，我真的不知道 ，但
within the you should write your code
内，你应该写代码
again expecting short counts as a
又怀孕了短算作一个
possibility and by the way that's one of
通过这一种方式的可能性和
the the headaches of using this
使用此的头痛
low-level i/o is is dealing with short
低级别的I / O是被处理的短
counts is not it's often a sort of a
重要的不是它往往是一个老的
nuisance of an application level so you
一个应用程序 级 的滋扰，所以你
don't usually package this up this kind
通常不包这件事这种
of low-level file IO into other
的低级别的文件IO到其它
libraries that you're calling it's only
图书馆，我们在调用它的唯一
really demonstrating this is the sort of
真正证明这又是何许
lowest level in the step and writing
最低水平步骤和写作
also can give you a short count for
也可以给你一个短数
example if you're sending packets over a
例如，如果你在发送数据包
network it will only send as many as is
网络是它只会发送尽可能多的
that packet can hold and then return
该数据包可以装，然后返回
back to you and you have to keep pumping
回给你，你必须保持抽
them out to send the different packets
他们去送不同的数据包
and so usually when you write code that
所以 通常当你写的代码，
uses this goal of while you have to
使用的同时，你有这个目标
anticipate these short counts so
预计这些短计数等等
professor O'Halloran wrote a package
教授奥哈洛伦写了一包
called Rio and you'll for now we'll just
叫里奥，你会现在我们就
talk about what this package is this is
谈论这个 包是这个
a package that you're really going to
一个包， 你真的要
want to you
想你
use for the the final web for the course
使用的最终网络的课程
and so for right now it's more of a
因此对于现在 它更多的是
high-level here's an example of code
这里高层次的 代码示例
that uses low-level IO
使用低级别的IO
and packages up in a way that makes it a
在某种程度上， 它使 一个封装起来
little bit more palatable so Rio
多一点可口所以里奥
provides actually a number of different
实际上提供了许多不同的
two different well actually three two
两种不同 以及实际三两
different levels of of interface to the
不同层次的界面给
file this file IO the lowest one is
文件该文件IO最低的是
basically just a fairly small wrapper
基本上只是一个相当小的包装
around the existing the the IO the reads
围绕现有的IO中的读
and writes you saw that will handle the
并写入您看到了将处理
short count issue and so when you say
短期计数问题，所以当你说
with Rio if you make a call to the read
里奥。如果您对读取调用
end function and you say some number
最终功能和你说一些数字
bite then that function will not return
咬 那么该 功能将不会返回
until it's read that number of bytes so
直到它读取的 字节，
better be careful that that that many
更要小心的是，许多
bytes are there if it's a network socket
字节是有，如果它是一个网络套接字
or a file well because it will flag an
或文件很好，因为它会标志的
error message if it will actually hang
如果它 实际上 将 挂起错误信息
up if it's a network connection waiting
，如果它是一个网络连接的等待
to read the bytes or return an error if
读取的字节或返回如果有错误
it hits a none into file what it's not
它击中一个没有 到文件就是它的不
expected and similarly with right n it's
预期 和类似的右 ñ它是
sort of a wrapper around the write
排序周围 写一个包装的
function that will deal with just loop
功能，将处理只是循环
until the short counts are taken care of
直到短计数照顾
and then there is a another class of i/o
然后有 一个其它类的I / O
that's called buffered i/o and this is
这就是所谓的缓冲I / O，这是
what you really want to use in practice
你真的要在实践中使用
and what you mostly use with the
和你大多与使用
standard UNIX iOS functions is that you
标准的UNIX iOS的功能是你
want to within the user code build up a
想用户代码中建立一个
little buffer of bytes that have either
字节的小缓冲区， 要么
been read in but not yet consumed by the
被读取但还未消耗
application program or you accumulate
应用程序或你累积
some number of bytes in your program
在程序中的一些字节数
before it actually shoved out into the
之前它实际上猛伸到
file or out onto the network and there's
文件或到网络上，并有
two versions of that one is a text
一个 两个版本是一个文本
oriented wine oriented eye
面向酒面向眼
and the other is just a byte oriented
另一种是只面向字节
i/o so let's go through the what the
I / O所以，让我们通过什么
functions aren't actually look at the
功能实际上并没有看
code for them so as I mentioned the ones
他们的代码，以便为我提到的那些
called readin and writin are just very
所谓阅读下载和以创作只是很
thin they have the same general
薄它们具有相同的 一般
semantics as the read and write but they
语义的读取和写入 ，但他们
deal with the short count issue
应对短期计数问题
so let's actually take a look at read em
所以让我们其实看看 读EM
so again readin is given a file
如此反复看书给出一个文件
descriptor a destination buffer and a
描述符中的目标缓冲器和
indication of how many characters how
多少个字符 如何 指示
many bytes it's supposed to read and
许多字节它应该阅读和
it's supposed to it's supposed to we
它应该它应该我们
returned I guess it will return either
返回的 我想这将返回
negative number if there's an error zero
负数，如果有一个错误 的零
if it's at an end of file or the number
如果它是在文件 或数 的结束
of bytes read so I guess I was a little
中读取的字节，所以我想我是一个小
bit I should have been more careful if
有点 我本来应该若再细心
it hits an end of file partway through
它击中中途文件的结束
it will return a short count but that's
它会返回一个简短计数但是这
the only case it won't return a short
唯一的情况下，它不会返回短
countess if there really it could have
如果真有 可能有 伯爵夫人
read more bytes so the main loop here
阅读更多字节，因此这里的主循环
you see is it keeps calling read over
你看到的是它不断给你打电话读了
and over again until it's happy ah one
一遍又一遍，直到它的幸福啊一个
way it can be happy is if it's read as
这样， 可以欣喜的是，如果它读作
many bytes as it was supposed to write
许多字节 它应该 写
read in the first place the other is
读 摆在首位，另一个是
that if it hits an error code and you'll
如果它击中了错误代码，你会
notice that
注意
oh and that there's some subtlety of
哦，并且有一些细微之处
tracking which type of error that is but
跟踪的错误的类型是但
in general the common cases it will
一般常见的情况下，将
return the negative number indicating an
返回指示一个负数
error if it if the number read is zero
如果错误如果阅读次数为零 ， 这
then that indicated into file and so
那么这表示进入文件 等
what it will return is as many bytes as
它会返回是作为多字节
it's read so return the short count and
它看了这么返回短期计数 和
here it's just saying okay I've read
在这里，它只是说，好吧，我读过
this number of bytes and increment and
这个字节数和增量和
decrement the right values so the point
递减正确的价值观，因此点
is that we'll keep looping keep doing
是 ，我们会继续循环继续做
reads until it either gets the number of
读取，直到它得到的数
bytes it should it hits an error or it
字节 它应该它击中了错误，或
encounters an end-of-file and you'll see
遇到档案结尾 ，你会看到
it has its checking for all these
它拥有所有这些 检查
different error conditions for every
每一个不同的错误条件
call it make so this code by the way is
叫它做所以这段代码的方式是
sort of typical that it looks a little
那种典型的，它看起来有点
messy when you first look at it but if
凌乱当你第一次看到它 ， 但 如果
you sort of study it it all makes sense
您排序的研究它，它都有道理
oh so now let's talk about buffered i/o
哦，所以现在让我们来谈谈缓冲I / O
and what buffered i/o is and this is a
什么缓冲I / O是， 这是一个
very important concept so it's part of
很重要的概念，所以 它 的 一部分
the reason we want to show you the code
我们想告诉你的代码的原因
for it so the idea of buffered i/o is
它所以缓冲I / O是想法
that that there's a buffer meaning just
那，有一个缓冲的意思只是
an array of characters array of bytes
字符 阵列的字节阵列
they're allocated and associated with
他们就分配和 关联
this particular file and the program if
这个特殊的文件和程序，如果
it's on a read what it will do is it
它是在读什么需要做的是它
will fill up this buffer it will give a
将填补这个缓冲区，它会给一个
read with a much larger number with a
用一个 更大的数字阅读
large number basically the size of the
大量基本 的大小
actual how much number you've allocated
实际你多少数量分配
for this buffer and the system will fill
这个缓冲区，系统将填补
that up with up to that number of
那以达到该数字 的
characters and then when the user
字符，然后该用户时
program wants to now look at this
程序要现在就来看看这个
get some bytes it will
得到一些字节它会
check do I already have some in the
检查我已经 有一些在
buffer that haven't been read yet and if
那些没有读入 ，如果缓冲区
so I'll just return those and if not
所以我就归还这些，如果不
then I'll refill the buffer so the idea
然后我会重新填充缓冲这样的想法
of it is instead of every time going to
它是不是每次都去
the operating system and asking for one
操作系统 和要求一个
character small number of characters
人物小数目的字符
that called the operating system says
那个叫操作系统 说
give me pretty much as many characters
给我几乎尽可能多的字符
as you've got up to some limit and then
因为 你已经得到了一些限制，然后
I'll just go away and what the
我就走开， 什么
application program I sort of pulled
应用程序我有点 拉
these out a couple bytes at a time but I
这一次输出一对夫妇字节，但 我
won't bug the operating system to do it
不会错误操作系统做
I being the real function and the way it
我是真正的功能 和方式，
does it is by just keeping a pointer of
确实它是 只是保持 的指针
the indicates what part of the the bytes
该指示字节的 哪一部分
that I've already brought in from the
我已经 从引进
operating system call but the haven't
操作系统 调用 ，但没有
been supplied yet to the application
尚未提供给应用程序
program and so in this sort of larger
程序并因此在这种大
picture of things if you imagine you're
事情的图片，如果你 想象 你
you're walking you through a file at any
你走你通过在任何一个文件
given point in time this buffer will
在给定的时间点这个缓冲区
represent some range of in that file
代表在该文件中的一些范围
where the green is the stuff that's
其中绿色的是这东西
already been read by the application
已经阅读应用
program the pink is the stuff that's
编程粉红色是这东西
been read but from the operating system
被读取但是从操作系统
out of a file but not yet read by the
出文件，但还没有被阅读
application program and the way this is
应用程序，这是方式
implemented once you think about it it's
实施一旦你想想 看 这是
not too hard to do is it associated with
不是太难做的是将其与关联
every file connection then is a file
然后每个文件连接文件
descriptor account that tells you how
告诉你如何描述帐户
many bytes there are that have not been
许多字节有没有 被
read yet a a pointer to where this this
但读指针AA 到 这个这个
changeover is and then the actual
转换是，然后将实际
storage of the the buffer itself the
的缓冲器的存储本身
characters allocated the bytes allocated
字符分配的字节分配
to the buffer itself
在缓冲区本身
and so here's an example then of of
所以这里有一个例子吧的
using Rio to do this echo that you first
使用力拓先做到这一点回音，你
read a line and reading a line means it
读出的线和读取线意味着它
will look for and stop at a line feed
将查找和换行符停止
character and writing it back out and
性格和写回出来 ，
again if you do the demo
如果再这样做了演示
of this code
这个代码
Hey
嘿
it's a little again you get let me just
这是一个小你又得到让我
trace right because it's a little hard
跟踪正确的，因为这是一个有点 硬
to see the read hard to figure out with
看阅读很难找出 与
so you'll see that it read the whole
所以你会看到，它读取 整个
line and now it's done to add the
行， 现在，它的完成添加
operating system-level it's written just
它 只是 写 操作系统级
one chunks worth one call to the the
一个块值得一个调用的
operating systems write function instead
操作系统编写 函数，而不是
of a byte by byte
按字节一个字节
okay so again I'm not going to go
好了，所以再次我不打算去
through all the code but it's actually
通过所有的代码 ，但它实际上是
worth your while to do this and by the
值得你这样做，由
way I've actually done some applications
办法其实我已经做了一些应用程序
where I took the Rio code I want to add
在那里我 接过 里约热内卢码我要 添加
some features to it but it's a very
一些功能， 但它是一个非常
useful starting point to be able to
有用的出发点是能够
build your own customized routines okay
建立你 自己的定制程序 好吗
so let's talk about some other parts of
所以让我们来谈谈其他一些地方
files one is that associated with a file
文件之一 就是 与文件 相关联
is what they call metadata so the data
是他们所谓的元数据，这样数据
are the actual contents of the files
是文件的 实际 内容
actual bytes inside that file but
该文件中的实际字节，但
there's a whole bunch of other stuff
还有其他的 东西一大堆
that's associated with the file
一个与该文件相关联
information about what type of file it
什么类型的文件的 信息， 它
is what protection read/write/execute
是什么保护的读/写/执行
protections it has some information
保护它有一些信息
about the ownership of that file what
有关文件的 所有权 什么
type it is
键入它是
and also the times associated with it
而 与之相关联 也是 时代
when was it created when was it last
是当它创造了它最后的时候
accessed and when was it last modified
访问和是什么时候最后修改
so that's known as a metadata and every
所以这被称为元数据和每
a file has that kind of information
文件具有那种信息
associated with it and you can actually
与之相关的 ，你其实可以
and it's in a data structure called a
它是在一个数据结构称为
stat data structure and you can if you
统计数据结构，你可以，如果你
want to write code that then sort of
要编写然后排序的代码
probes the directory structure of a of a
探针的的目录结构
file system you can make a call to the
文件系统， 您可以 对通话
stat function and it's given the the
统计功能， 它给了的
path name of the file you want to stat
要统计 的文件的路径名
and then a pointer to it one of these
然后 指向 它 的 指针 这些中的 一个
stat data structures and then that our
统计数据结构，然后，我们的
data structure will get filled in by the
数据结构将由得到填补
information for this particular file and
这个特定的文件信息和
then you can test various attributes
那么你可以测试各种属性
about that file and see basically get
有关文件看看基本上得到
the information that that's stored here
那这是这里存储的信息
and there's all these nasty compile time
并有所有这些讨厌的编译时间
constants that you use or macros that
您 使用常量或宏
use to
使用
look at and examine these visa metadata
看待和审视这些签证 元
so here's a example I will do it but
所以这里有一个 例子， 我会 做，但
it's a function called stat check it's
这是一个被称为STAT检查它的功能
in the same directory and so if you
在同一目录中，因此，如果您
check some file or typically say well
查了一些文件，或通常说的不错
it's a regular file and yes you're
这是一个常规文件，并且是你
allowed to read it but now if I call
允许，如果我现在打电话给看，而是
chmod to eliminate set all the
chmod 来消除设置所有
protections to zero you know say no you
保护到零，你 知道说没有你
can't read it now and so again that's
现在不能等看了一遍那
just making use of this Gator here so
只是把这个鳄鱼的这里，所以
now this is the part that gets a lot
现在这是 得到了很多 的部分
more tricky it's how our files how are
更棘手的是如何我们的 文件是如何
all this information about file is
有关文件的所有信息 是
actually represented by the programs
实际上是由 计划 代表
question yes stat gist
问题是统计要点
I'll tell you one way you can find out
我会告诉你，你可以找到出路之一
what step does if you say man 2 stat
如果没有你说哪一步的人 2统计
you'll get more than you want to know so
你会得到更多的比你想 知道 这么
in general you know if you say man's
一般来说，你知道，如果你说男人
debt it'll give a unix of command that
债务都将发出命令的UNIX是
you can use to step a file so I can say
您 可以 使用步骤文件，所以我 可以说
stat dot and it will print out some
统计 点，它会打印 出一些
information about a file in this case of
关于这种情况下的文件信息
my local directory let's see I can stat
我的本地目录，让我们看看 我能 STAT
any file here and it will print out some
这里的任何文件，它 会打印出一些
some cryptic information about it but if
这件事，但是如果一些神秘的信息
you say man 2 stat the UNIX man pages
你说男人2统计 UNIX手册页
are divided into different categories
被分成 不同的类别
and things that our system calls UNIX
和事情， 我们的系统调用UNIX
system library calls are typically in
系统库调用通常在
section 2 of the man pages and so that
手册页和使第2
will return information about it but the
将返回 关于它 ，但 信息
main point of it is stat is then a
它的点主要是统计是那么
function that you call where you give it
你 打电话，你给它 的功能
a path name and a pointer to a buffer
的路径名和指向缓冲区的指针
that you want it and it will then fill
你想它，然后它会 填满
in the contents of the buffer with the
在缓冲器与内容
information about that particular file
关于 特定文件 的信息
and the form that it fills it in is one
而且它填补它的 形式 是一个
of these data structures called a struct
称为一个结构这些数据结构的
step and that's pretty typical of a lot
退一步，这是相当 典型的很多
of these functions is that they have
这些功能是 他们有
some predefined struct and if you want
一些预定义的结构，如果你想
to get it if you want to get information
得到它，如果你想 获得信息
you pass you allocate one of those
你通过你分配其中的一个
struts you pass a pointer to it and then
支柱你一个指针传递给 它，然后
the library function will fill in the
库函数将填补
details does that make sense
细节 做 是否有意义
okay so now let's look at some of the
好吧所以现在让我们来看看一些
internal data structures that the
内部数据结构 ，所述
operating system maintains regarding the
操作系统维护有关
files associated with a program and this
用 程序和这个 相关的文件
is a source of really nasty exam
真是讨厌考试的来源
problems I'll just warn you so you're
问题我只是提醒 你，你是
going to want to read this part of the
会想读的这部分
book carefully study the practice
仔细研究书的做法
problems look at the old exams because I
问题看旧的考试，因为我
can guarantee you you're going to get
可以向你保证，你会 得到
some of these on the final that's a
其中的一些在最后，这是 一个
promise and they can be infinitely
承诺他们可以无限
obscure so we can we can torch you with
晦涩所以我们可以我们可以火炬你
these so the main point is that
这些所谓的主要观点是，
associated with any executing process
与任何执行的进程 相关联的
which you can think of a process is a
你能想到的方法是
running program is a something called
正在运行的程序是一个叫什么
the descriptor table and what that
在描述符表和什么
contains is for every open file that you
包含对每一个打开的文件，你
have it has a pointer to a data
有它有一个指向 数据
structure called an entry in a table
结构称为一个表中的条目
that's maintained by the operating
那年代由操作维护
system globally which describes each of
系统全局描述 每个
the open files actually each of every
打开的文件实际上每个每
time a file is opened that allocates a
一次文件被打开时会分配
record in this open file table and so as
记录在该打开的文件表，从而
I mentioned file descriptor 0 1 & 2 have
我提到文件描述符0 1＆2具有
specific meanings and the other files or
具体含义和其他文件或
other ones that you've opened up during
你已经在开辟了其他的
the course of your program execution and
你的程序执行的过程中和
have not yet closed so that so each of
尚未关闭，以便使各
these then is a reference to a
这些然后是所涉及的参考
particular open file and it gives
特别是打开的文件，并让
information about that file and it also
有关文件，而同样的信息
gives the position in the file that
给文件中的立场
currently is that I told you every time
目前 ，我每次告诉你
you open a file there's a for a regular
你打开一个文件有一个 用于常规
file at least there's an Associated
文件中至少有一个关联
position of where in the file
在文件中的位置在那里
it was your last reader right or where
这是你最后一次正确的读者或者
would you be your next free to write and
你会成为你的下 自由 书写和
so that's the file pause and there's
所以这是该文件暂停，并有
also a reference count which is used by
也其中使用由基准计数
the operating system to keep track of
操作系统跟踪
because we'll see it's possible to have
因为我们会看到它的可能 有
multiple multiple processes sharing an
多个多个进程共享一个
entry in this Open File table and it
在此 打开文件表项，它
uses this reference count which is
使用 此引用计数是
standard way of keeping track of memory
跟踪的内存的标准方式
allocation to know when it no longer
分配知道它何时不再
needs that entry if when there's been
如果 需要 时一直是入门
enough when the file is no longer
够当文件不再
accessible and therefore this entry is
提供服务， 因此此内容
not needed so for every one of your open
所以无需为你打开每一个
files that will have an entry in this
将在这一个项文件
table and this table as I said is shared
表和该表作为我说的是共享
across the whole operating system and
在 整个操作系统和
then associated with every file is
然后与相关的每一个文件是
called the V node which stands for
称为其代表在V节点
virtual node and this is where that
假想节点而这正是该
contains the sort of information about
包含排序的相关信息
this file in particular where is it
该文件特别是它在哪里
stored on this information that you can
存储这些信息 ， 你可以
get from stat and things like that how
从统计之类的东西怎么弄
big it is and and things like that so
大是和之类的东西 ，以便
that's for every every file in the
这是在每家每户的文件
system actually has a V node entry
系统实际上呈V节点条目
whether it's open or closed now this can
无论是打开或关闭现在这样可以
get complicated so for example if within
获得复杂，所以 ，例如，如果内
a single program you call open twice on
你叫开 上两次 单节目
the same function you'll actually get
你实际上会得到同样的功能
two different file descriptors and
两种不同的文件描述符和
you'll be able to access that same file
你就可以访问同一文件
and have two different positions in it
并在 这 两个 不同的位置
and it makes sense if you imagine you're
它是有道理的 ，如果你 想象你
reading from a file and you might want
从文件中读取，你可能想
to read from two different positions in
从两个不同的位置读
that file within the same program and
同一 程序 内的文件 和
you can do that that's perfectly legal
你 可以做， 这是完全合法
you just call open twice and that will
你只需要调用开放两次，这将
keep track of two
跟踪两
positions so the point is these file
位置，以便点是这些文件
descriptors might be referring to the
描述可能是指
same file but they're actually at
同样的文件，但他们在实际上是
different positions within the file and
该文件内的不同位置和
that can happen also if you're if you've
如果你是，如果你已经能也发生
opened a file for both reading and for
打开一个文件供读取和
writing and you're writing ahead and
写，你 写进取，
then reading characters bytes that have
有那么读取字符 字节
already been written that makes sense
已经写 是有道理的
it's not such a good idea to have two
它不是这样的 有两个 是个好 主意
different write file opens that are
不同的写入文件打开是
writing simultaneously you can mess up
同时写入可以胡来
the file pretty badly that way but
文件相当严重这种方式，但
there's nothing in the operating system
没有什么操作系统
that prevents you from doing that so it
阻止你这样做，所以它
won't it's not a good idea but it's a
会不会这不是一个好 主意，但它是一个
legal operation so that's the point is
合法经营所以这点是
you have to distinguish at what level is
你有什么水平的区分
sharing taking place and you see that if
分享拍摄的地方，你看到，如果
you have two different table entries
你有两个不同的表项
sharing one file then that what's
共享一个文件，那么这是什么
different there is that you can be
不同的存在 ，你可以 是
working at different file positions
在不同的文件位置工作
similarly of course the more common
同样当然更常见
thing is you have two different open
事情是你有两个不同的开放
files in there refer to different files
在那里的文件指的是不同的文件
but now and this is where life gets
但现在，这就是生活变得
exciting if you call Fork you remember
令人兴奋的，如果你调用 fork 你还记得
about Fork that it spawns a child but
关于叉，它产生一个孩子，但
that child inherits a lot of information
那个孩子继承了大量的信息
from its parent and one of the things
从其父和 的事情之一
that inherits is its descriptor table it
继承是它的描述符表它
gets a replica of that descriptor table
获取描述符表的副本
and so now both the parent and the child
所以现在的家长和孩子都
have identical entries in their
在相同 的条目
descriptor table and so they're sharing
描述符表，所以他们正在共享
files but not at the file level but at
文件，但不是在文件级别，但在
the Open File table and what that means
打开文件表，这是什么意思
is if the parent does a read it'll bump
是，如果家长不读它会碰到
along the file position and if the child
沿着文件位置，如果孩子
know does it read it will it will see
知道 不读这本书是将它会看到
this from this new position so you can
这个从这个新的位置，这样就 可以
see why the exam problems get really
为什么考试问题得到真正
interesting
有趣
because that will keep track of all
因为这将跟踪 所有的
these different possibilities and
这些不同的可能性 和
they'll do different things and so and
他们会做不同的事情，所以 和
then of course the parent or the child
那当然父母或 孩子
can start opening and closing their own
可以开始打开和关闭自己
files as well and that will get very
文件以及，这将变得非常
messy and here's what you see the reason
混乱和这里就是你看到的原因
for having reference counts here that if
这里有引用 计数，如果
you have a lot of forking going on then
你有很多的分叉，然后去的
you can create multiple pointers to this
您可以创建多个指向这个
a table entry and in order to really
一个表条目，并以真
really close the file each of these has
真正关闭文件每一个都有
to call closed before the file is truly
调用关闭之前，该文件是真的
truly closed from an operating system
从操作系统真正关闭
perspective so there's other fun things
透视所以有 其他有趣的事情
that make life interesting too and
使生活变得有趣和太
contribute to the exam problem
有助于考试题
possibilities what is it call called
可能性是 什么 呢打电话叫
dupe - and the purpose the dupe - is -
重复数据删除 -和宗旨 的欺骗-是-
excuse me duplicate a entry in the
原谅我重复在一个条目
descriptor table and the most common use
描述符表和最常见的使用
of that is a IO redirection that either
的这是一个IO重定向，要么
greater or less than sign to either
大于或小于符号要么
redirect read the instead of from
重定向宣读了代替
standard input from a file or instead of
从或而不是一个文件标准输入
writing to standard output to write to a
写到标准输出写入到
file and the way the operating system
文件和路操作系统
actually implements that is shortly
真正实现 即不久
after starting the program it will call
启动程序后， 它会调用
called Duke - to make it so that the
叫杜克- 使它 从而使
file descriptor 1 is not the standard
文件描述符1是不是标准
output of the for this process but it's
输出这一过程，但它是
actually the original standard output
其实原来的标准输出
but it's actually a descriptor for the
但它实际上是对一个描述符
file that it's supposed to write to and
文件它应该 写入和
same with if it's doing input
同样，如果用它做输入
redirection
重定向
and but you can call Duke to yourself
并且您也可以致电 公爵给自己
and do these kind of things and these
做这类事情 和这些
actually good reasons for doing so
其实很好的理由这样做
so in particular imagine I open the file
所以特别想像我打开文件
and standard output points to the sort
和标准输出指向排序
of normal thing and I open a new file I
正常的事情，我打开一个 新的文件，我
call it B and then I call Duke to excuse
叫它B，然后我叫杜克原谅
me
我
and now what both file descriptor 1 and
现在什么都文件描述符1 和
file descriptor for are sharing this
对于共享 此文件描述符
entry in the file table and you see the
在文件表项，您将看到
reference count of 2 and so in order to
的2个参考计数， 因此为了
really close it then what would
真正关闭它，然后 会是什么
typically happen at this point is the
通常发生在这一点上是
this is happens before it starts to your
这是发生在开始之前你
program you'd want to close file
计划你想关闭文件
descriptor 4 and in fact there's a lot
描述4，实际上还有很多
of bugs you can make by not closing
错误的你可以不关闭使
files it's easy to make mistakes when
文件很容易犯错误的时候
you have multiple entries in these
你必须 在 这些 多个 条目
tables yep no C if I call close this one
表YEP没有C，如果我把 这个关闭一个
it just decrement sits reference count
它只是坐在递减引用计数
but this remains a valid entry here
但是这 仍然是一个有效的项 在这里
while a yes but due to will decrement
而肯定的，但由于意志减量
the reference count of the original dupe
原来 欺骗 的引用计数
to goes backwards from where you think
到会倒流，从那里 你想
it should so do two is the I want what
它应该这么做二是我想要的
what I referred to for example file
我提到的示例文件
descriptor I want file descriptor for to
描述我想文件描述符到
become what I can use to and refer to
变成什么样，我可以使用，并指
with file descriptor 1 here it will
与文件描述符1 这会
actually decrement the reference count
实际上递减引用计数
of this before it done does the copy
这是做之前做副本
otherwise it would create like a an
否则会造成类似的
orphan in this table right
孤儿在此表中右
Oh so anyways dupe 2 also is a powerful
哦，所以反正 欺骗2 还是一个功能强大
but dangerous mechanism so now finally
但危险的机制， 那么现在终于
let me just mention the much more common
让我 提更常见
i/o that application programs use is
的I / O的应用程序是使用
what's known as the standard i/o and
什么作为标准I / O和
that's what's documented in knr and it's
这就是在KNR记录，它的
actually part of the the C standard all
实际上C标准的一部分， 所有
these different functions and so the
这些不同的功能， 因此在
main feature it adds is sort of like
它增加了主要特点是有点像
what you saw with the REO package it
你与选举事务处包看到它
adds buffering so it doesn't have to do
增加了缓冲，因此它没有做
this low-level stuff and it avoids all
这种低层次的 东西，它避免了所有
than some of the nastiness and the way
比一些污秽和方式
it works is what we've already seen it
它的工作原理是什么，我们已经看到它
uses buffering to do a vio so just as an
使用缓冲做VIO所以只是作为
example
例
here's some code that calls printf one
这里是一些调用printf 一个代码
character at a time to print the word
角色在同一时间 以打印 字
hello but if I run that and is trace it
你好，但如果 我运行 ， 并 跟踪它
you see that there's only one system
你看到有只有一个系统
call to two right and it works the same
呼叫两个 权利，它的工作原理 相同
way you saw with the Rio code it builds
这样你用 它构建 了 里约热内卢 见到 代码
up a buffer and it's not until this call
一个缓冲区，它不是直到这个电话
to F flush that forces the output to
到F齐平，迫使输出
actually be a printed output usually
实际上是一个打印输出通常
that happens automatically actually if
该 自动发生，如果实际
you print up a line feed it will flush
您打印一个换行符就会刷新
it so that I think that called F wash is
它使我认为，称F是洗
probably redundant here so and so that's
这里大概冗余谁谁那
the benefit so buffered i/o is much more
益处所以缓冲的I / O是更
efficient because it because of the
高效的，因为它是因为
buffering so as a result we've now seen
缓冲这样的结果我们已经看到
three different types of i/o there's the
三种不同类型的I / O还有的
low-level i/o called you referred to as
低级别的 I / O叫你被称为
UNIX i/o you saw this package that was
UNIX I / O您看到这个包 是
written specifically for the book and
专门为这本书撰写和
for the course called Rio and then
名为里约热内卢 ，然后 过程
there's a much larger and in fact richer
还有一个更大的，实际上 更丰富
set of i/o functions provided by the
通过所提供的一组I / O的功能
UNIX standard library so you might ask a
UNIX标准库，所以你可能会问一个
couple questions one is well why the
夫妇的问题一个很好的理由
heck did you write this when you've
赫克你写这个，当你
already got that if if UNIX provides
已经有了 ，如果如果 UNIX提供
buffered i/o why did you do it yourself
缓冲I / O 你为什么要自己做
and the reason is this stuff doesn't it
其原因是这 东西对不对
works really well for the i/o you do to
作品真的很好的I / O你做
a terminal or defiled but it doesn't do
终端或玷污，但它不会做
very well with network connections it
非常好，网络连接 它
wasn't really designed for that and so
是不是真的专为 等
it gets really messed up and so the main
它就会真的搞砸等主
reason you're going to find yourself
原因你会发现自己
using this is when you're starting to
使用这是当你开始
use network connections oh the other
使用网络连接哦 其他
thing is these do not coexist very well
就是这些不 共存的很好
buffered i/o with a reow i/o
缓冲I / O与reow的i / o
because they each maintain their own
因为它们各自保持自己的
buffers and they don't know about each
缓冲区， 他们不知道每个
other and they get terribly confused so
其他的，他们得到严重的混乱等等
you kind of have to pick one or the
你种必须选择一个 或
other
其他
with respect to any
对于任何
ticular i/o connection and don't try to
满足特殊的I / O连接，不要试图
mix and match them so like I said UNIX
混合所以就像我说的 UNIX与它们匹配
i/o then the low-level stuff from an
I / O，则 低级别从东西
application perspective it's like really
应用角度看，它就像 真的
painful to use especially with short
痛苦与短期特别 使用
counts and error codes and and all that
计数和错误代码，并和所有的
stuff and so in general you want to
的东西， 所以一般要
either write your own package or use
无论是写自己的 包或使用
some other package around it and so as I
其他一些包装它周围，使我
said standard i/o it gives you printf
该标准的I / O它给你的printf
and scanf and all these nice features
和scanf 而所有这些不错的功能
it's uniform it exists on all systems
这是它存在于所有系统的统一
it's reasonably standardized so in
它是合理的标准化，从而在
general then use the the standard i/o
一般然后使用标准的I / O
for most year of day-to-day uses of
对于一天到一天的用途最年
files I'll use the raw IO for low-level
文件我将使用原始IO 低 级别
stuff like when you have to and partly
东西时，你必须 和 像 部分
it turns out signals are not you
事实证明，信号不是你
shouldn't use standard i/o when you're
当你不应该使用标准I / O
writing signal handlers and then the REO
编写信号处理程序，然后REO
you're going to find useful for in
你会找到有用
particular for doing networking one
特别是做 一个 网络
other thing that you should one bug that
其他的事情，你应该一个错误，
students do over and over again in this
学生在此做了一遍又一遍
course is they try to do a line oriented
当然是他们试图 做定向的线
i/o on things that aren't lines so like
我的事情是不是线 / O 等等之类
a JPEG image or something like that and
JPEG 图像或 类似的东西和
the reason that's important is that
这是很重要的原因是 ，
these functions are treat the end of
这些功能 是治疗结束
line character zero a is a very special
行字符零是一个非常特殊的
character they'll stop reading or
性格，他们会停下来读取或
something like that or if it's going
类似的东西，或者如果它是怎么回事
between Windows and UNIX it will
Windows 和UNIX之间它会
actually change one from carriage
真正 改变一个从车厢
returns from line feed to carriage
从换行返回到托架
return line feed sin way functions like
换行罪路功能，如
steer land and steer copy will stop when
引导 土地和引导副本时停止
they hit a null byte and that's not what
他们打空字节，这不是什么
you want to do when these are network
你想，当这些做网络
packets you're trying to send out so be
你想包发送出去，所以要
careful some of the functions you've
小心一些，您对功能
used a lot and you're very familiar with
使用了很多， 你很熟悉
may be completely inappropriate for
可能是完全不合适的
are things where you're doing binary of
事情，你正在做的二进制
data or you're communicating over
数据或者 您进行通信
networks and things like that so be sure
网络之类 的东西，所以一定
you understand what you're doing when
你知道 你在做 什么 时
you start to use these kind of functions
你开始使用这些种功能
oh so those do you really want to know
哦， 所以那些你 真的想知道
this stuff there's there's a fellow
这 东西 有有一个老乡
named Richard Stevens who unfortunately
名叫理查德·史蒂文斯不幸的是谁
died awhile quite a while ago but his
死了一段时间 前一段时间，但他的
books live on and there's various people
书籍住在这里面的各种各样的人
have signed up to become co-authors with
已经签约成为合作作者用
him in his absence and creating new
他在他的缺席，并创造 新的
editions of these books that used to
这些书是用来版本
date back way far so and if you really
追溯到方式到目前为止，如果你真的
want to know how this stuff works you
想知道 这个东西是如何工作的 你
want to be the 8th programmer these
想 成为 程序员第八 这些
books are the best you can get but I'll
书籍是最好的，你可以得到 ，但我会
also warn you your bookshelf will become
也提醒你你的书架将成为
very heavy laden because there's there's
很重担，因为有有
volumes one two and three and then
体积的一种二和三， 然后
there's networking books and Stevens is
有网络书籍和史蒂文斯
like a encyclopedic reference but
像百科全书参考，但
they're excellent books if you really
他们是优秀的书籍，如果你真的
want to understand something
想了解的东西
read Stevens oh and there's another book
阅读史蒂文斯噢，还有 另一本书
that is just specific to Linux that's
这 仅仅是具体到Linux这
fairly nice and somewhat it's very
相当不错的， 有点它是非常
detailed but since it's only trying to
详细，但因为 它只是试图
deal with Linux it's a little bit less
对付Linux的是有点少
of weird than trying to read Stevens
不是试图去阅读史蒂文斯 的 怪异
because Stevens will say in this version
因为史蒂文斯将在这个版本说
of UNIX it works this way in this
UNIX的是这样工作 在这
version it works that way and blah blah
版本，它的工作原理是这样等等等等
blah and it's all different and it will
等等这一切都不同 ，它会
drive you crazy but Stevens is still
你发疯 ，但史蒂文斯仍然是
it's an outstanding set of books ok so
这是一个优秀的一套书确定，所以
this is an example and I'm not going to
这是一个例子，我不打算
go through it but these are the kind of
通过它，但这些都是 那种
things that we use to torture students
的事情，我们 用它来 折磨学生
that you open some file descriptors and
您打开某些文件的描述符和
you do some dupes and you do some Forks
你做一些受骗者和你做一些福克斯
and so you end up with a real spaghetti
所以你结束了一个真正的意大利面条
for all the pointers and what's shared
所有指针和分享的内容
and what's not shared and then you ask
而什么是不共享的，然后你问
what will this print and of course you
是什么内容的打印，当然你
have to trace through in great detail
要通过很详细追查
what's really going on so those are
到底发生了什么的所以这些都是
in the book and I recommend you work on
在这本书，我建议你在工作
some of those okay that'll do it for
其中一些好吗 那将做它
today then
那么今天